<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Fumbling Physicist</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Fumbling Physicist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The basics of quantum-dot qubits</title>
      <link>/posts/silicon-qubits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/silicon-qubits/</guid>
      <description>So many qubits, so little time At the time of writing this there are at least five competing technologies vying for the quantum computing throne. Superconducting qubits, trapped ions, neutral atom arrays and silicon (CMOS) qubits are the top contenders. The various so-called &amp;ldquo;color centers&amp;rdquo;, a prominent example of which are Nitrogen-Vacancy centers in diamonds, arguably lagging behind.
Using an eye-rollingly terrible expression, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;The Zoo of Qubits&amp;rsquo;. They only reason I am willing to use it is because I do believe some of them are cute but useless, some are scary and may bite you, and It&amp;rsquo;s very likely most of them will be extinct soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barnes Hut in Rust</title>
      <link>/posts/barnes-hut-in-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/barnes-hut-in-rust/</guid>
      <description>Apprenticeship The education system in the UK has an apprenticeship path built into it. This path allows young people who wish to finish the purely academic chapter of their studies at 16 to acquire vocational skills. I&amp;rsquo;ve never done an apprenticeship myself, but I was enamored by the idea when I heard about it as a schoolboy.
How I imagine an apprenticeship, which may be very different from what a British apprenticeship actually looks like, is like a movie montage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum engineering (in hebrew)</title>
      <link>/posts/quantum_eng_cross_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/quantum_eng_cross_post/</guid>
      <description>This post was originally posted on qubit.il, the israeli quantum community.
 驻 砖 专注.    砖 砖转 20 砖  -21. 转转 转 注 专转 驻专爪转 专, 住 住祝  注&amp;quot; 爪转 拽 砖转砖   注 专 专抓 注 驻  驻拽转.   驻专爪 拽转.  注砖 转 驻 转  转专  驻转 驻专爪 拽转,  砖 砖 砖, 驻  转 专. 拽爪专:  砖 驻 住驻专 砖 转  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cat Qubits</title>
      <link>/posts/catqubitpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 09:40:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/catqubitpost/</guid>
      <description>A very short intro to bosonic codes (Cats) This is an informal introduction to Bosonic qubits in circuit QED greatly inspired by: Atharv Joshi et al 2021 Quantum Sci. Technol. 6 033001
Bosons ぁ? It&amp;rsquo;s not strictly important we understand what bosons are. However, I know that at least for me seeing a funny word I don&amp;rsquo;t know is a distractor when reading something new. I just have to know what the word means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arithmetic on Quantum Computers</title>
      <link>/posts/arithmetic-on-quantum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 17:16:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/arithmetic-on-quantum/</guid>
      <description>How do you calculate 1+1 on a quantum computer? Uri Levy&amp;rsquo;s question There&amp;rsquo;s something about being part of a group that&amp;rsquo;s wonderfully transformative. You drink coffee with some people, day in, day out, for a few years, and start speaking a common language. You work with them, commute with them, and walk past them in the halls. And you end up being like them or at least trying to be. Working in the Weizmann Institute&amp;rsquo;s (WIS) complex system department was indeed a very transformative environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About me My name is Gal. I&amp;rsquo;m an experimental physicist from Herzliya, Israel, a lovely coastal town just north of Tel Aviv.
I am married to Danit and we have two cute kids.
I did my physics Ph.D. at the Weizmann Institute under the supervision of Prof. Ofer Firstenberg, where I was the first student in the lab. My main experiment involved cold atoms and quantum optics using Rydberg atoms. I was also passionate about writing scientific outreach articles at the time, something I would like to revive in this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
